A Guide to the David Rockefeller papers, Photographic collections, Numbered Albums FA1316
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Nancy and Richard Rockefeller's Wedding, 2007; Some black-and-white images.; Many images are grainy. (Box 145)
  DR attended celebration of Richard and Nancy's wedding held at Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden in Seal Harbor, Maine.
  142 images.
- New York Compilation Album, 2000-2003 (Box 146)
  DR with various friends or family members at events in New York. Includes Brooke Astor's 100th birthday, Rockefeller University's centennial celebration, the dedication of the Peggy Rockefeller Plaza in Rockefeller Center, a family wedding, DR's 85th birthday, and an event at the Peggy Rockefeller Rose Garden at the New York Botantical Gardens.
- Tarrytown and Ireland Family Album, 2000 (Box 147)
  Compilation album of family gatherings in 2000, first at an all-family event at the Playhouse in Pocantico Hills, New York. This was probably the combined birthday celebration for DR (85th) and Laurance Rockefeller (90th). The bulk of the images in the album are from DR's family trip to an estate in Ireland.
  74 images.
- New Hampshire Trip, 2003 (Box 148)
  DR visit with family in New Hampshire. All of his children joined him at a family member's farm.
- New York City Event for Princess Chulabhorn Walailak of Thailand, 1988 (Box 149)
  DR and PR attended a formal event honoring Princess Chulabhorn Walailak of Thailand. Also attending were Birabhongse Kasemsri, a future Thai ambassador to the United States. Laurance Rockefeller, Mary F. Rockefeller, Barbara Walters, Joshua Lederberg, Michael Forbes, Nancy Kissinger.
- Nigeria and Senegal Trip, 1964; Some black-and-white images. (Box 150)
  DR trip for Chase Manhattan Bank to Nigeria and Senegal. He met with Ado Abdullahi Bayero, the Emir of Kano in Nigeria.
- Norway Trip, 1975 June; Color is faded on most images and some are grainy. (Box 151)
  DR and PR trip near Trondheim, Norway, for a salmon fishing trip with friends on the Vefsna River.
  78 images.
- Oklahoma Delegation Compilation Album, 1966 (Box 152)
  Album presented to DR in 1966 by a delegation from Oklahoma, with images from throughout the state.
- Panama Trip for Americas Society, 1984, 1984 October (Box 153)
  DR went to Panama as a representative of the Americas Society. He formed a committee at the request of President Ronald Reagan and reported back to him at the conclusion of the trip. DR met with President Nicolas Ardito Barletta and U.S. Ambassador Ted Briggs while in Panama. Images are from the reception hosted by President Barletta.
- Panama, Peru, Chile, and Colombia Trip, 1954, 1954 January; Black-and-white images. (Box 154)
  DR joined officers from other banks, Peter Grace from Grace Companies, and Assistant Secretary of Commerce Sam Anderson to visit these four countries to explore investment opportunities.
- Paraguay Trip, 1980, 1980 November (Box 155)
  DR and PR trip to Paraguay, which was part of a trip that also included Argentina, Brazil, Chile, and Panama. DR visited Chase Bank branches in Paraguay and met with President Alfredo Stoessner. Robert Douglass and Linda Douglass accompanied them. Images are from a reception, likely hosted by Ambassador Conrado Pappalardo.
  55 images
- Paris Trip, 2000, 2000 November 16 (Box 156)
  DR received the Grand Cross of the French Legion of Honor at a formal ceremony in Paris.
- Peggy's 80th Birthday Celebration, 1995 September (Box 157)
  Surprise party for Peggy thrown by staff members for her 80th birthday.
- Peggy and David's Celebration of PR's 75th Birthday, 1990 September (Box 158)
  Formal event to celebrate PR's 75th birthday. Guests include Henry Kissinger, George Shultz, Akio Morita, Peter Peterson, Walther Moreira Salles, Jamie Wyeth, Cyrus Vance, and Dick Voell.
  71 images.
- Peggy Dulany's Coming Out/Debutante Party, 1963; Black-and-white images. (Box 159)
  Party for DR's daughter Peggy's debut.
  89 images.
- Peter Peterson Award Luncheon, 2008 (Box 160)
  Luncheon held in honor of Peter G. Peterson at the Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) in New York. Attendees include DR, Agnes Gund, Glenn Lowry, and Mimi Haas.
- Philippines Trip, 1978, 1978 February 3; Some black-and-white images. (Box 161)
  DR trip to Manila, Philippines, on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. He met with cabinet member Cesar Virata--a future Prime Minister of the Philippines--and President Ferdinand Marcos.
- Philippines Trip, 1974, 1974 November 2-5; Black-and-white images. (Box 162)
  DR trip to Manila, Philippines, on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank that was the first leg in a multi-part trip to Asia. He also travled to Thailand, India, Pakistan, and Iran. While in Manila, DR met with President Ferdinand Marcos and attended a Chase International Advisory Committee meeting. Most of the images are from a formal dinner at the Malacanang Palace. The Committee also held a dinner for the President and Imelda Marcos. Later, DR gave a talk at the Magsaysay Award Foundation and visited the Corregidor Island historical site.
  100 images.
- Pocantico Hills Album on Carriage Ride Event, 1981, 1981 Spring (Box 163)
  DR and PR hosted an event for carriage owners to ride through the Kykuit estate property in Pocantico Hills, New York. A reception at the Coach Barn on the estate followed.
- Pocantico Hills Album on Dinner for Chase International Advisory Committee, October 27, 1991, 1991 October 27; Most of the images have slight emulsion damage (small white spots). (Box 164)
  DR and PR hosted a reception at Kykuit and dinner at the Coach Barn in Pocantico Hills for the Chase Manhattan Bank International Advisory Committee, which DR chaired at the time. Attendees include Henry Kissinger, Nancy Kissinger, Gustavo Cisneros, Tom Labrecque, Sheila Lebrecque, Robert Douglass, and Linda Douglass.
  80 images.
- Pocantico Hills Album on Carriage Ride Event, 1996, 1996 June (Box 165)
  DR hosted a carriage ride at Pocantico Hills, New York. Guests included Rodman and Sasha Rockefeller as well as several friends. NOTE: The digital images are of the Pocantico carriage ride as described despite inconsistencies between the names of the JPEG format and the TIFF format of the digital photo files.
- Poland and Hungary Trip, 1989 March (Box 166)
  DR and PR visit Poland and Hungary as part of the Chase Manhattan Bank's Corporate Program. In Poland, they met with Lech Walesa, the founder and leader of the Solidarity movement and recent Nobel Peace Prize winner. He later served as president of Poland. They also met with Jozef Glemp, Archbishop of Warsaw. Katherine Graham, publisher of the Washington Post, was also on the trip. In Hungary, they met with General Secretary Karoly Grosz and also with businessman Sandor Demjan.
- President Ronald Reagan's Visit to Kykuit, 1986 July; Many of the images are blurry or the color is off tone. (Box 167)
  DR and Laurance Rockefeller hosted President Ronald Reagan and First Lady Nancy Reagan at Kykuit while they were in New York for the celebration of the 100th anniversary of the Statue of Liberty. The album includes extensive images of the tour of Kykuit and its grounds, with a dinner at Kykuit that was also attended by Mary French Rockefeller, Happy Rockefeller, and Peggy Rockefeller. The album also covers the regatta in New York Harbor that was part of the celebration on July 4. The President and the Rockefellers were aboard the yacht The Highlander for that event.
  210 images.
- Progenitors Compilation Album, Part 1, 1956; Most images are black and white.; Image quality is fair to poor throughout the album. (Box 168)
  Compilation album of Rockefeller and McGrath family members. It also includes several outdoor images of Maine and sailing.
  47 images.
- Quattrone Family Album, 2012, Image quality varies. (Box 169)
  Compilation album for DR from grandson Michael Quattrone and his family.
  75 images.
- Quito, Ecuador Trip for Chase Manhattan Bank, 1985 February; Black-and-white images. (Box 170)
  DR trip to Quito, Ecuador, on behalf of Chase Manhattan's International Advisory Committee. In additional to tours and meetings, DR received La Orden Nacional "Al Merito" from President Leon Febres Cordero at the presidential palace.
- Ringing Point, Seal Harbor, Maine Trip, 2012 (Box 171)
  DR visited his home in Seal Harbor, Maine, with friends Gus Cisneros and Patricia Cisneros. They visited the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden and sailed on the "Sea Smoke."
- Guest book from "Teepee", 1964-1983 (Box 172)
  This box contains the guest book of signatures for "Teepee" from 1964 to 1983, which was the custom-designed guest house at DR's home (Colombier) on St. Bart's, in the Caribbean. There are no photographs in this box.
- Rio Negro, Brazil Trip, 2002 January (Box 173)
  DR cruise with family and friends to Rio Negro, Brazil, in January 2002. Hiking, fishing, sailing, hunting for beetles were some of their activities.
  107 images.
- Rockefeller University Landscape Album, 1985 May (Box 174)
  DR and Annette Reed donated landscape lighting for the campus on the occasion of the RU Founders Ball in 1985. This album shows the campus with the new lighting.
- Rome, Italy Trip, 2011 June (Box 175)
  DR trip to Rome with family and friends. Sightseeing and a celebration of his 96th birthday.
  30 images.
- Russia Trip, 1997 (Box 176)
  DR trip to Russia, including travels in Kazakhstan and Moscow.
  58 images.
- Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, and Oman Trip, 1990, 1990 February (Box 177)
  As co-chair of the Corporate Program of the Council on Foreign Relations (CFR), DR led a trip to Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, and Oman that included meetings and sightseeing.
  60 images.
- Saudi Arabia Trip, 1981 (Box 178)
  DR trip to Saudi Arabia that included visit to Jeddah. Images of reception and dinner.
- Maine Trip with Family, 1999 (Box 179)
  DR trip to his home Ringing Point, in Seal Harbor, Maine. Joined by Laurance Rockefeller, other family members, and staff.
- Maine, Buckle Island Trip, 1966, 1966 Summer; Color is faded in most images. (Box 180)
  DR and PR trip to Buckle Island, Maine, with family. Sailing, woodworking, hiking, fishing.
- St. Bart's Trip Album, 1967 (Box 181)
  DR and PR's trip to Colombier, their house on St. Bart's in the Caribbean, with friends and family. Happy Rockefeller joined them. Images are of the exterior of the house, the property, and the surrounding beach area.
- David and Peggy's Wedding, 1940 September 7; Black-and-white images. (Box 182)
  DR and Peggy's wedding ceremony was held in Bedford, New York, at St. Matthew's Episcopal Church. John D. 3rd was best man. Richard Gilder and brothers Nelson, Laurance, and Winthrop were ushers. Photos include John D. Jr. and Abby Rockefeller, as well as Peggy's parents, Sims and Neva McGrath.
- Family of Man Award Ceremony for Prime Minister Lester B. Pearson, 1965; Black-and-white images. (Box 183)
  The Society for the Family of Man awarded its annual prize to Canadian Prime Minister Lester Pearson. He was the 1957 Nobel Peace Prize recipient for his role in diffusing the Suez Crisis in Egypt. David Rockefeller served as Family of Man Award Dinner chair.
  The Society for the Family of Man was an international and interfaith organization founded in 1963 by the Council of Churches of the City of New York to honor outstanding examples of excellence in society.
- Four Trees Sculpture, Jean Dubuffet, Installation and Unveiling, 1972 August-October; Black-and-white images. (Box 184)
  Jean Dubuffet's monumental sculpture "Group of Four Trees" was installed in front of Chase Manhattan Bank headquarters in August of 1972. An unveiling celebration took place in October, with the artist in attendance at a luncheon hosted by DR and a dinner hosted by Brooke Astor.
  43 images.
- Ivory Coast Trip, Part #2, 1971, 1971 November; Black-and-white images. (Box 185)
  DR trip to several African nations on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Three days in Ivory Coast (Cote d'Ivoire) included meeting with President Felix Houphouet-Boigny, who awarded DR with the Ordre Nationale Ivoiren.
- Ivory Coast Trip, Part #3, 1971, 1971 November; Black-and-white images. (Box 186)
- Milan, Italy Trip for Chase Manhattan Bank, 1957 October; Black-and-white images. (Box 187)
  DR trip to Milan, Italy, to meet with Giuseppe Lauro of Innocenti Corporation, on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. Tour of Innocenti's popular Lambretta motor scooter factory.
- Saudi Arabia Trip for Chase Bank, 1994 (Box 188)
  DR trip to Saudi Arabia on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 1995, Some images are damaged. (Box 189)
  DR and PR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with family and friends. Sailing, hiking, visiting gardens, attending commemorative event. Visit with Mary Todhunter Clark Rockefeller, perhaps the last images of her with PR.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 1996 (Box 190)
  DR visit to Seal Harbor, Maine, with family and friends. Sailing, hiking, touring gardens. Visits with Laurance Rockefeller, Mary French Rockefeller, Andrew Wyeth, Jamie Wyeth.
  General
  153 images.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 1917-1921, Black-and-white images.; Image quality is poor. (Box 191)
  Early images of the Eyrie, the home of David Rockefeller's parents in Seal Harbor, Maine, as well as of John D. Rockefeller Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, their children, and some of the surrounding area.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 1997 (Box 192)
  DR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with family and friends. The initial photo of PR is from a previous year. Sailing, hiking, whale watching, visiting gardens, berry picking.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 1998 (Box 193)
  DR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with family and friends. Sailing, hiking, wildlife, wildflowers, gardens. Family celebration, likely for DR's birthday.
  124 images.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 1999-2000 (Box 194)
  DR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with family and friends. Sailing, hiking, gardens, golfing. Aerial views, possibly of Seal Harbor property.
  161 images.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 2001 (Box 195)
  DR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with friends and family. Sailing, hiking, touring gardens and farms, golfing, horseback riding, bird watching. A few images with Laurance Rockefeller.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 2002 (Box 196)
  DR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with family and friends. Sailing, hiking, bird watching, special event (at which DR spoke), garden tours.
  122 images.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 2003-2004 (Box 197)
  DR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with friends and family. Sailing, hiking, garden tour, family visit.
  105 images.
- Seal Harbor, Maine Compilation Album, 2005 (Box 198)
  DR trip to Seal Harbor, Maine, with friends and family. Sailing, hiking, garden tours. Photo of DR's niece, Laura R. Chasin.
- Shoshone-Wind River Wilderness Family Trip, 1990 July (Box 199)
  DR and PR trip with family to the Shoshone and Wind River Wilderness in Wyoming to celebrate their 50th wedding anniversary. Hiking, horseback riding, camping, swimming.
  72 images.
- South Africa Trip, 1995 (Box 200)
  DR trip to South Africa, likely on behalf of Chase Bank's International Advisory Committee. Meetings with Nelson Mandela and F.W. de Klerk.
- South Venezuela Trip, 1988, Mostly black-and-white images. (Box 201)
  DR and PR trip through southern Venezuela with the Cisneros family. Includes sightseeing, views of Mt. Roraima, capybaras (world's largest rodents), boat excursions, hiking in the tepuys (tabletop mountains).
- Spring Moon Construction and Launch, 1986 (Box 202)
  Album of the construction of DR and PR's boat, Spring Moon. Shows it being built, christened (by PR), and launched.
  46 images.
- St. Bart's Compilation Album, 1983-1987 (Box 203)
  DR and PR trips with family and friends to Colombier, their home on St. Bart's (Saint Barthelemy), in the Caribbean.
- St. Bart's Trip Album, Part 1, 1972-1973, Some images are damaged, creased, or faded. (Box 204)
  DR and PR trip to their home, Colombier, on St. Bart's in the Caribbean with family and friends. Sailing, touring the island and beaches, swimming, watching wildlife, visiting nearby town. Interior and exterior of home. Exterior of guest house (known as Teepee).
  137 images.
- St. Bart's Property Album, 1972-1973, Some black-and-white images. (Box 205)
  Album of DR and PR's home, Colombier, on St. Bart's in the Caribbean. Images taken for an architect or realtor's report. DR is not in the images. Includes exterior and interior of the house, exterior of the guest house ("Teepee"), and views of the surrounding property.
- St. Bart's Album, May 1969, 1969 May; Some black-and-white images. (Box 206)
  Exterior and interior images of Colombier, DR and PR's house on St. Bart's (St. Barthelemy), in the Caribbean. A few family images as well.
- St. Bart's Christmas and New York Compilation Album, 1966, Some black-and-white images. (Box 207)
  Compilation album from DR and PR's properties on St. Bart's (St. Barthelemy) in the Caribbean and at Hudson Pines Farms in Pocantico Hills, New York. Images are exterior shots of the properties, animals, gardens, scenery. Also images of Rockefeller Center in Manhattan.
  88 images.
- St. Bart's Album, 1965 (Box 208)
  Small album of images of Colombier, DR and PR's house on St. Bart's (St. Barthelemy), in the Caribbean. Images of the house, the property, the water, and aquatic plants and animals.
- Stone Barns Center and Property Album, 1987-2004 (Box 209)
  Album of images of the Stone Barns Center and surrounding property in Pocantico Hills, New York. Includes the ribbon-cutting ceremony in 2004, when the center was opened as a nonprofit farm and education center for food and agriculture. DR and members of his family led the ceremony and tours of the new facility. The album also includes earlier images of the property when the cattle farm (at Hudson Pines) held an auction.
- Tarrytown Album of Pocantico Hills Properties, 1997-1998 (Box 210)
  DR shows friends around Pocantico Hills properties, including tour of gardens at Hudson Pines, carriage ride, tour of gardens at Kykuit, and tour of grounds of Playhouse.
- Thailand Trip, Part 1, 2001, 2001 January (Box 211)
  DR trip to Thailand. Sightseeing at temples, markets, gardens, boat tours, elephant ride, tour to border gate of Myanmar, local villages, shrines.
  201 images.
- Thailand Trip, including Cambodia, Part 2, 2001, 2001 January (Box 212)
  DR trip to Thailand and Cambodia. Sightseeing mostly in Cambodia: Genocide Museum in Phnom Penh, Killing Fields, temples/shrines, Angkor Wat temple. DR had a meeting with King Bhumibol Adulyadej of Thailand.
  136 images.
- Thailand Trip, 1962, Black-and-white images.; Some images are poor quality. (Box 213)
  DR and PR trip to Thailand. Meeting with King Bhumibol Adulyadej. Attendance at ceremony, possibly graduation. The images are from 1962, although the prints were made and assembled in the 1990s or 2000s.
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden Compilation Album, 1968-2003 (Box 214)
  Compilation album that focuses on the flowers and plantings in the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden in Seal Harbor, Maine. Most images are from the summer, although there are a few of the garden from autumn and winter.
  163 images.
- The Kids Compilation Album, 1945-1959; Most are black-and-white images.; Image quality varies. (Box 215)
  Compilation album of DR and PR's children during their youth.
  84 images.
- The Netherlands Trip, 1950; Black-and-white images. (Box 216)
  Images of PR with ducklings, provided by the management of Chateau de Wittenburg, Wassenaar, The Netherlands, following their trip.
  6 images.
- Tikal Ruins, Guatemala Trip, 2005 (Box 217)
  Album compiled by DR's grandsons of their trip with DR to Tikal, Mayan ruins in Guatemala rainforest. Most images are of the vegetation and of insects (beetles, butterflies) and spiders. The final image is of DR's dog, Tori.
- Tokyo, Japan Trip, 1994 (Box 218)
  DR's trip to Tokyo to view art exhibit on impressionism. Hosted by Kanichiro Ishibashi, chair of Bridgestone Tire Company and president of the Ishibashi Foundation.
- Tokyo Praemium Imperiale Event, 1989 (Box 219)
  DR traveled to Tokyo to attend an awards ceremony hosted by the Praemium Imperiale, Japan's arts society. Images of speeches, medal recipients, and performances. Attendees included Ronald Reagan, Helmut Schmidt, I.M. Pei, Jacque Chirac, Umberto Mastroianni, Sir Edward Heath, David Hockney, and Emperor Akihito.
- Toluca, Mexico Trip, 1972, 1972 March; Black-and-white images. (Box 220)
  DR trip to Toluca, the capital of the state of Mexico, on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank's International Advisory Committee. DR met with the governor of the state and the mayor of Toluca during a presentation on new urban development in Toluca. He also toured the pyramids at Teotihuacan.
- Venezuela Trip, 1991, 1991 August (Box 221)
  DR visit to Venezuela: image with Gustavo Cisneros and Eugenio Mendoza at the presidential summer residence.
  2 images.
- Colonial Williamsburg, Virginia Trip, 1986, 1986 October (Box 222)
  DR and PR trip to Colonial Williamsburg with Tish and Bill Hewitt. Tours of Williamsburg and carriage rides through the park.
  56 images.
- World Trips Compilation Album, 2000-2001 (Box 223)
  DR trips to various countries, some with family and others with friends. Countries visited include Mexico, Ireland, France, Ecuador, Italy, and Scotland. The final images are of a Council of the Americas event in Washington, DC, at which Dick Cheney spoke.
  129 images.
- Yucatan, Mexico Trip, 1985, 1985 February; Some images are grainy. (Box 224)
  DR trip to the state of Yucatan, Mexico, while traveling on behalf of Chase Manhattan Bank. He visited the Mayan ruins in the city of Uxmal and at Chichen Itza.
  99 images.
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden, 2005 (Box 225)
  Seal Harbor, Maine.
  54 images
- Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Garden, 2011 (Box 226)
- Baja California, Mexico Trip, 1994 (Box 227)
  DR and PR sailing trip around Baja California, Mexico. Rick Salomon and Rick Fleishman joined them.
- Bangkok, Thailand Trip, 1987 (Box 228)
  DR and PR trip with family to Bangkok, Thailand, including celebration of the beginning of the year of the Rabbit.
- Botswana Trip, 2008; Some images are grainy or blurry. (Box 229)
  DR trip to Botswana with family. Many landscape, floral, and wildlife images.
  179 images
- Chase Alumni Recollections, 2014; Image quality varies. (Box 230)
  Compilation album of images of DR with various Chase Bank employees or employee headshots over several years.
- Christmas at Seal Harbor, Maine Album, 2005, 2005 December (Box 231)
  DR and family celebrate Christmas at their home, Ringing Point, Seal Harbor, Maine.
  77 images, some duplicates.
- Costa Rica Album, 2007, Some black-and-white images. (Box 232)
  Possible DR trip to Costa Rica, although he is not in any images. Possibly promotional tourism images of wildlife, flowers, church, banana processing plant, and local residents.
- David Rockefeller, Jr. Childhood Portraits, 1942; Black-and-white images.; Some images are grainy or faded. (Box 233)
  Baby pictures of DR Jr. with PR, with DR, and with a dog.
- La Romana, Dominican Republic Trip, 2009 (Box 234)
  DR trip to La Romana, Dominican Republic, with friends: Gustavo Cisneros and his family, Glenn Lowry, and Susan Lowry.
- La Serenisima, Dominican Republic Trip, 2007, Images are grainy. (Box 235)
  DR trip to La Serenisima, Dominican Republic, with friends, including the Cisneros family.
  66 images.
- Family Trip to Celebrate DR and Peggy's 55th Anniversary, JY Ranch, Wyoming, 1995 (Box 236)
  All of their children and some grandchildren joined DR and PR in Jackson Hole, Wyoming, to celebrate their 55th wedding anniversary.
  83 images.